Resume 2022-10-20, 3:01 PM

CHINMAYA SUKUMAR

DATA ANALYST

Summary

I am a Data Analyst specializing in integrating the field of engineering into the world of Data Science. I have experience in wrangling, processing and visualizing data and training and evaluating AI/ML models on said data. My background experience is in steel and plastics industries. I am adept in Python, SQL, pandas, matplotlib, scikit-learn, keras and Tableau.

Employment

Suchint Business Solutions

Mississauga, ON Jan. 2019 to Current

Technical Analyst

Involved in discovering applications for various plastics including silanes, flame retardants, and UV stabilizers

ArcelorMittal Dofasco

Hamilton, ON May 2016 to May 2017

Co-op Lab Technician
Responsible for customer qualifica

Responsible for customer qualification of automotive grade steel for an OEM manufacturer

Worked in a cross-functional New Product Development team

Projects

Springboard Capstone Project

Oct. 2022

In an effort to aid engineers in the design process of a grade of steel, a model was successfully built that accurately predicted the strength of a grade of steel given solely its chemistry. The data was processed and visualized then trained on a Gradient Boosting Regressor. Accuracies were 98% when cross-validating.

Springboard Guided Project

In a hypothetical scenario, using data from over 300 US ski resorts, a Random Forest Regressor model was trained and successfully predicted what additions to the amenities of a specific ski-resort would result in the greatest increase in revenue. Data was wrangled, EDA and PCA were performed before initiating the modelling proces

Engineering Capstone Project

2015 to 2016

Worked on an industry-led project to determine the ideal steel chemistry to prevent hydrogen-induced cracking of steel. Was technical lead in a 5 person dynamic team

Contact

- **■** sukumar.chinmaya@gmail.com
- **4**166711481
- Mississauga, ON

in linkedin.com/in/chinmayasukumar/

n chinmayasukumar

Education

McMaster 2011 to University 2018
B. Eng Masters Engineering 2018

Springboard May 2022 to Dec. 2022

Certificate Data Science Career Track 2022

6-month intensive course in data science, machine learning, Python and SQL 500+ hours of hands-on course material, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 2 in-depth portfolio projects. Mastered skills in Python, SQL, data wrangling, data visualization, hypothesis testing, and machine learning.

Skills

DATA SCIENCE

Python

SQL

Tableau

pandas

NumPy

Scikit-learn

keras

git

matplotlib

https://resume.creddle.io/